[wind blowing]
[SITARA] What?
Princess Sorghaghtani
refused the marriage after all?
That's right.
Quite surprising, isn't it?
So what will happen
to Lady Töregene?
Her freedom depended
on the princess marrying
Prince Güyük!
What did Empress Boraqchin
have to say about it?
Calm down, will you?
I'll tell you everything.
Sorghaghtani Beki.
This is what is best
for the Mongols.
And it is to your benefit
as well.
I must recommend that you humbly
accept our offer.
♪
I truly appreciate
your courtesy.
However, I then remember
the wise words
our great foremother,
Alan Gua, said to her five sons:
"A single arrow may be broken
with ease
but five arrows bundled together
shan't ever be broken."
Great Kha'an,
Tolui was one of the arrows
bundled at your side.
It falls upon me
to raise his sons.
They are young
and fragile arrows
still needing to be crafted.
[BORAQCHIN]
The House of Tolui on its own?
She refuses to be engulfed
by the House of Ögedei.
[SORGHAGHTANI]
I'm quite sure your retainers
-feel the same way.
-[gasps]
Isn't that right, General Ilüge?
Huh? Uh, yes.
[SORGHAGHTANI]
You are the head retainer
serving the House of Ögedei.
I imagine the Great Kha'an
trusts you
with his finest treasure.
A sign of his
utmost confidence in you.
[SITARA] His finest treasure?
Does she mean Lady Töregene?
Yes.
She's in
General Ilüge's territory.
[Ilüge groans]
[♪ opening theme song playing]
[ÖGEDEI]
You seem to be in a foul mood.
[BORAQCHIN] Do I?
Sorghaghtani sent a messenger.
If it's to the
Great Kha'an's liking,
she's happy
to offer up 4,000 tents
from the House of Tolui.
The same territory and people
I had planned to deprive her of
all along.
She's making a mockery of me.
Are you angry at me
for what I have done
to your family?
[ÖGEDEI] How could I be angry?
Because of you, I am finally
able to do as I wish.
You have my thanks.
However, I must say this,
going forward,
please don't involve
Töregene anymore.
She is someone precious to me.
I want her protected.
I understand.
[SHIRA]
Prince Güyük and Sir Qadaq
are heading
for General Ilüge's lands.
General Ilüge served
as the Great Kha'an's tutor
for many years.
His influence rivals
that of the imperial family.
Not even Prince Güyük
can just go there
without establishing
a good reason first.
Shira, we need to hurry.
You'd better hold on tight then.
Let's go.
[SHIRA] Looks like
a rough road ahead of us.
♪
[SLAVE] Uh? [exclaims]
Excuse me, Lady Töregene.
-[slave exclaims]
-[WOMAN] Uh?
[chuckles]
Have you mistaken me
for that silly girl again?
[slave screams] My apologies.
Oh, there are way too many tents
for me to remember
which is which.
-[footsteps]
-Huh?
[Qadaq sighs]
[ILÜGE] Why,
if it isn't Prince Güyük.
What brings you
to my humble abode?
[GÜYÜK] Uh...
Our Lady Töregene is here,
isn't she?
May we speak with her?
Now why would you assume
something like that?
Be reasonable.
Would we have come all this way
if we weren't certain?
It is kind of a long story,
but let me tell you...
[SHIRA] They want us to find her
and make sure
that she's still safe
while they try to keep
his attention elsewhere.
Where would we start, even?
Forget about success.
If we're caught,
it could mean our heads.
Hey, where are you going?
-[gasps]
-[SHIRA] Hurry.
[ELJIGIDEI]
This could be dangerous.
We must do everything we can
to conceal the fact that
Lady Töregene is here.
[Sitara gasps]
[ARGHUN] Hm?
Uh?
[dog whines]
[ELJIGIDEI]
What's wrong? Let's go.
[ARGHUN] Right.
[ELJIGIDEI]
And how is Lady Töregene faring?
[ARGHUN]
I went to see her just earlier.
She's doing well.
[sighs] Did you hear
what they said?
That means we've confirmed
that she's safe,
and we can head back for now--
[grunts]
Hey, wait! Ah!
[cloth rustles]
[footsteps]
Lady Töregene,
I thank you for waiting.
I've brought your meal.
[sighs] You're late.
[SLAVE] My deepest apologies.
I got lost again.
[Töregene sighs]
Why is there no urum?
Hm? Urum's been out of season
for quite some time now,
my lady.
I was just asking.
Now, leave me.
Uh! Of course!
[exclaims]
Oh, Fatima.
[SITARA] Lady Töregene.
Lady Töregene.
-Lady Töregene.
-[SHIRA] Hey, stop!
-We need to head back!
-[gasps]
[SLAVE] Lady Töregene
is so hard to please.
[Sitara gasps]
♪
[gasps softly]
[TÖREGENE] Hm?
[exclaims] Lady Töregene!
Fatima? What are you doing here?
Thank goodness.
You're really all right!
I finally get to see you again.
[Töregene gasps softly]
♪
I don't understand.
Even though I betrayed you...
[SITARA] Lady Töregene, look.
Despite everything,
you managed to protect them.
All the feelings...
that are the most precious
to me.
No.
The most precious to us.
[TÖREGENE]
The Great Khatun told me this:
In my previous days,
I waited upon Empress Khulan.
[Töregene gasps] Khulan?
The one who taught me
how to find the joys in life.
And who offered herself
to the Mongols
to protect the Merkits
facing ruin.
Khulan.
[BORAQCHIN] I always had a sense
that she bore
feelings of resentment.
It seems that even to this day,
you harbor those same feelings
toward the Mongols.
Did she really?
Please allow me
to lend you my assistance.
So that you may be
able to achieve
what she wished she could.
[TÖREGENE] I thought my chance
to kill Ögedei had come.
The Great Khatun told me
that you were not to be trusted.
[Sitara gasps]
I was a fool.
[exclaims] I fell for her lies,
and betrayed
both you and Khulan.
♪
[SITARA] Lady Töregene...
I, too, found myself confronted.
With the thought
of abandoning the past
and moving on with my life...
I ended up betraying
you as well.
Fatima sure
is taking her time talking.
We need to get going
before we're discovered.
[gasps]
Wait, is that really
who I think it is?
Uh, no way.
Sorry, but you're
on your own now.
[running footsteps]
[footsteps]
-[cloth rustles]
-[ÖGEDEI] I'm coming in.
[BOTH] Uh?
[gasps]
[SITARA] Great Kha'an!
And what is it you want?
If my fate is to be executed,
then let us be done with it.
Of course not.
I have a favor to ask of you.
[TÖREGENE] Hm?
You may enter.
-[Töregene gasps]
-Hello, Mother.
My darling Güyük!
[SITARA] "My darling Güyük?"
Oh, my goodness,
what are you doing here,
my little darling?
Is my little boy all right?
You didn't run
into anything scary, did you?
I'm quite well, Mother.
Please try to calm yourself.
[Töregene sighs]
I beg of you, Mother, come back
with me to my territory.
[TÖREGENE] Huh?
It lies to the west,
on the steppe between the
Altai Mountains and Tian Shan.
The winters are cold,
but there's plenty of water.
And the pastures are lush.
And what's more,
it is far away from here.
[Töregene gasps]
[Sitara gasps softly]
♪
I ask the same, Töregene.
The court is much too tumultuous
a place for you and Güyük, no?
If you will agree to go,
I won't ask any more of you.
All I want
is for you to be happy.
[SITARA] I see.
That would certainly resolve
everything tidily.
Empress Boraqchin wanted
Prince Güyük
and Princess Sorghaghtani
to get married
as a condition
for Lady Töregene's freedom.
Her aim was to remove
the three of them
from the imperial court.
That particular scheme of hers
didn't bear fruit, though.
But with this plan,
all three of them
will leave the political stage
still the same.
And it isn't a terrible proposal
for Lady Töregene, either.
[GÜYÜK] All right then, Mother.
Tomorrow, I'll come fetch you.
Sorry for such a commotion.
[ILÜGE] Will that be all?
[ÖGEDEI] Yes.
-But before I go...
-[ILÜGE] Oh?
[ÖGEDEI] Töregene...
If I may, can I speak
with your lady-in-waiting?
[TÖREGENE] Huh?
[SITARA] Huh?
Oh.
Why do you wanna talk to me?
So you're Fatima, correct?
Möge spoke of you.
I hear you get lost easily.
Uh...
[chuckles nervously]
And I've also heard that
you're a scholar's daughter.
Are you knowledgeable
in the stars?
The stars?
[ILÜGE] Please, Great Kha'an!
You really
mustn't speak directly
to someone so far beneath you!
[ÖGEDEI] Hmm.
Allow my son
to relay the words for you.
-Go!
-Oh, all right.
[ELJIGIDEI] The emperor asks,
"Are you knowledgeable
in the stars?"
Why, yes. I am. Considerably so.
"Why, yes, I am.
Considerably so." Sire!
Good. Would she happen to know
why the stars move across
the night sky?
[ELJIGIDEI] Oh.
[ELJIGIDEI] "Good.
Would she happen to know
why the stars move
across the night sky?"
The Great Kha'an asks.
Um...
Well, that much I do know.
I read it in a book
by Al-Biruni.
♪
"He created the sun, moon,
and the stars.
All are subject to His command."
So it is written in the Quran.
This means that
the movement of the stars
is a blessing
granted to us by Allah.
Furthermore, the heavens
are eight layers of spheres
revolving in place.
And we reside in the center
of those spheres.
-Hmm.
-[ELJIGIDEI] That's a lot.
[ÖGEDEI] Oh? How amusing.
-[Eljigidei gasps]
-Did you say amusing?
Hey, you don't talk to him!
Yes. Quite different
from what I know.
When I was younger, I was told
that in the night sky,
the stars are livestock
tied to a pillar in heaven.
That pillar is the star
in the north sky
that never moves.
With all due respect,
-that is merely a superstition.
-[gasps]
[ÖGEDEI] You think so?
For all that we know
and don't know,
our world could be
a galloping horse
bound to a rope.
Riding that horse...
myself and Boraqchin.
Sorghaghtani and Tolui.
And of course, you and Töregene.
All of us on its back,
circling as we head toward
the same destination.
Utter nonsense.
It's against the very concept
of science.
-Science, you say?
-[Eljigidei gasps]
[Sitara sighs]
Yes, science.
The laws that govern nature.
The work of Allah,
who created the world
and bestowed it to us.
Science is the discipline
that seeks to study this.
Well, in that case,
there are spirits
that the kams speak of.
I'd say their existence explains
the laws of nature well enough.
You're wrong.
The Quran tells us
that Allah made the stars
move across the sky
to help give us direction.
The positions and paths
of the stars are calculated
with Earth at its center,
giving us results
without any contradiction.
What more proof
could you possibly need
to see that this is the truth?
Anything else is a mere figment!
[breathes heavily]
[wind blows]
[Ögedei chuckles]
I see now.
You must get along
very well with Töregene.
What if you and I made a wager?
A wager?
[ÖGEDEI] Yes. But one where
all you have to do is watch.
In the days ahead,
I will bring prosperity
to the Mongol Empire.
With methods unlike those
of my father or Tolui.
So that you and Töregene
can find happiness.
Find happiness?
[ÖGEDEI] That's right.
When I first
laid eyes upon Töregene,
I realized what my duty is.
I must create
the Mongol Empire anew...
Solely because of the look
in her eyes.
You've lost your homeland
and family as well, no?
Your eyes earlier,
they were the very image
of hers on that day.
So watch me with those
very same eyes of yours.
If you two manage
to find happiness here,
victory is mine.
♪
[breathing heavily]
[grunting]
[screaming]
[thuds]
[panting]
[wind blowing]
[bleating]
[TÖREGENE] Fatima?
[Sitara gasps]
-Fatima.
-Oh, Lady Töregene!
Are you all right?
Uh, yes. But how are you doing?
You know, Fatima...
I've been thinking
more about it.
I think I won't be going
to live with my Güyük.
[Sitara gasps]
Why, doing that would be
just what
the Great Kha'an wants.
And the very thought of it
infuriates me.
[Sitara gasps]
Fatima, will you...
Will you fight by my side
once more?
♪
[Sitara breathes softly]
The thing is...
I'm not clever,
not even a little bit, you know?
♪
[Sitara gasps]
Let the two of us
summon a storm upon them.
[SITARA] That's right.
I'm not fighting
the Great Kha'an by myself.
I'm not alone anymore.
This empire...
And the Mongols who chose to
take everything we had from us.
We can never allow them
to be thought of as good.
Fatima, now it's our turn.
To become the witches.
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[wind howling]
[SITARA (ADULT)] That year,
the winter came
as it always does.
And eventually,
so, too, did the summer.
On the steppe, the grass sprouts
anew once more,
and the sheep graze peacefully
upon the soft buds.
♪
Everything perfectly unchanging.
The steppe, same as ever.
But is it really?
[TÖREGENE]
Good day to you, Great Khatun.
Fine weather we're having.
[SITARA]
It's as though it embodies
the growing prosperity
of the empire.
Yes, I would agree.
Second Empress Töregene,
and her lady-in-waiting,
Fatima.
[Sitara chuckles]
♪
[SITARA (ADULT)] That year,
Emperor Ögedei
appointed a governor
to oversee Persia.
And the land that Sitara
once called home
finally fell under
the permanent rule
of the Mongol Empire.
However...
the dispute that this position
would cause...
eventually, would turn into
a great storm
that would shake
the empire to its core.
But no one knew this yet.